Rubin, Harold; Papers apap032
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Neighborhood Associations Files, 1972-2002; 3; 2.0 cubic ft.
  - The Neighborhood Resources Center, 1975-1992; 3.2
    - General Correspondence, 1976-1988 (Box 5 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 30)
    - General Correspondence, 1978-1989 (Box 5 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 31)
    - Minutes, 1975-1977 (Box 5 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 32)
    - Minutes, 1978-1979 (Box 5 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 33)
    - Minutes, 1980-1982 (Box 5 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 34)
    - Minutes, 1983-1985 (Box 5 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 35)
    - Minutes, 1988-1989 (Box 5 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 36)
    - Property Assessment Guide, 1991-1992 (Box 5 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 37)
    - Publications, 1976-1989 (Box 5 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 38)
  - The Center Square Association, 1969-1979; 3.3
    Contains information on the building of a McDonald's, Lawsuit vs. Board of Building and Zoning Appeals (1977), police court, Terry Fox properties, and other zoning cases.
    - Lawsuit vs. Board of Building and Zoning Appeals, 1977 (Box 5 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 39)
    - McDonald's, 1972 (Box 5 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 40)
    - Police Court, 1975-1976 (Box 5 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 41)
    - Terry Fox Properties, 1977-1979 (Box 5 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 42)
    - Zoning, 1969 (Box 5 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 43)
    - Center Square Association (Box 5 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files))
      Jay Street 175 (Knickerbockers Apts.).
      Jay Street 182 to 201.
      128 Lancaster Street (Tri City Women's Center).
      Lancaster Street 151/153.
      Lancaster Street 152.
      Lancaster Street 171-173 (8-13-73).
      Lancaster Street 177.
      So. Susan Street 96/98.
      State Street 256.
      State Street 258 (former Russell Sage).
      State Street 281-283 (Camary Inc.).
      State Street 281/283.
      State Street 312.
      State Street 314.
    - Center Square Association, 1958-1979 (Box 5 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files))
      Center Square Association, Formed, 1958.
      Center Square Association, 1958.
      Center Square Association, 1959.
      Center Square Association, 1960s.
      Center Square Association, 1970.
      Center Square Association, 1971.
      Center Square Association, 1972.
      Center Square Association, 1973.
      Center Square Association, 1974.
      Center Square Association, 1975.
      Center Square Association, 1976.
      Center Square Association, 1977.
      Center Square Association, 1978.
      Center Square Association, 1979.
    - Center Square Association, 1980-1989 (Box 5 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files))
      Center Square Association, 1980.
      Center Square Association, 1981.
      Center Square Association, 1982.
      Center Square Association, 1983.
      Center Square Association, 1984.
      Center Square Association, 1985.
      Center Square Association, 1986.
      Center Square Association, 1987.
      Center Square Association, 1988.
      Center Square Association, 1989.
    - Center Square Association, 1990-1999 (Box 5 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files))
      Center Square Association, 1990.
      Center Square Association, 1991.
      Center Square Association, 1992.
      Center Square Association, 1993.
      Center Square Association, 1994.
      Center Square Association, 1995.
      Center Square Association, 1996.
      Center Square Association, 1997.
      Center Square Association, 1998.
      Center Square Association, 1999.
    - Open Container Ordinance (Box 5 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files))
    - South Mall Environs - Study Leading to Preservation Zoning in South Mall Environs, 1972-1974 (Box 5 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files))
  - The Capitol Hill Architectural Review Commission, 1971-1988; 3.4
    Contains agendas, appointments, minutes, and recommendations, and information on sandblasting, and tax delinquency.
    - Agendas, 1975-1988 (Box 6 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 1)
    - Appointments, 1974-1981 (Box 6 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 2)
    - Capital Hill Architectural Review Commission, 1974-1985 (Box 6 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 3)
    - Capital Hill Architectural Review Commission, 1975-1978 (Box 6 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 4)
    - Minutes, 1975-1977 (Box 6 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 5)
    - Minutes, 1978-1980 (Box 6 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 6)
    - Minutes, 1981-1984 (Box 6 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 7)
    - Minutes, 1985-1987 (Box 6 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1971-1986 (Box 6 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 9)
    - Recommendations, 1977-1979 (Box 6 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 10)
    - Sandblasting, 1975-1979 (Box 6 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 11)
  - The Coalition for Effective Code Enforcement, 1974-1978; 3.5
    Includes newspaper clippings and records on the organization.
    - Coalition for Effective Code Enforcement, 1974-1977 (Box 6 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 12)
    - Coalition for Effective Code Enforcement, 1975-1976 (Box 6 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 13)
    - Coalition for Effective Code Enforcement, 1976-1977 (Box 6 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 14-15)
    - Tax Delinquency, 1977-1978 (Box 6 (3-Neighborhood Associations Files), Folder 16)
- Clippings/Miscellaneous Files, 1972-1980; 4; 0.7 cubic ft.
  Contains files kept by Harold Rubin relating to his concerns as a civil servant and in the Albany community. They include clippings about the State Investigation Committee (SIC) hearings into the awarding of governmental contracts in Albany; Albany code enforcement and community development issues. Includes one folder labeled Code Enforcement which inaddition to newspaper clippings includes Rubin's correspondence as head of the Center Square Association Zoning Committee in 1973-1974 with city officials including Mayor Corning, copies of speeches Rubin made to local organization, and drafts an article on code enforcement Rubin wrote which was published in the Times Union relating to the enforcement of zoning ordinances in Albany.
  - Albany, State Investigation Committee (SIC), Investigation, 1972 (Box 6 (4-Clippings/Miscellaneous Files), Folder 17)
  - Code Enforcement, 1973-1979 (Box 6 (4-Clippings/Miscellaneous Files), Folder 18)
    (includes drafts of Rubin articles and speeches).
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6 (4-Clippings/Miscellaneous Files), Folder 19)
  - News Clippings, Albany, 1974-1976 (Box 6 (4-Clippings/Miscellaneous Files), Folder 20)
  - News Clippings, Albany, 1980 (Box 6 (4-Clippings/Miscellaneous Files), Folder 21)
  - Community Development, Albany, Undated (Box 6 (4-Clippings/Miscellaneous Files), Folder 22)
  - City of Albany Charter Revision Commission, 1996-1998 (Box 6 (4-Clippings/Miscellaneous Files), Folder 23)